<mes:Structure xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:com="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/common" xmlns:data="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/data/structurespecific" xmlns:str="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/structure" xmlns:mes="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/message" xmlns:gen="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/data/generic" xmlns:footer="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/message/footer">
  <mes:Header>
    <mes:Test>false</mes:Test>
    <mes:Prepared>2023-09-04T16:31:44.701872</mes:Prepared>
    <mes:Source xml:lang="en">Generated by message_ix_models 2023.5.32.dev20+g8d51636</mes:Source>
  </mes:Header>
  <mes:Structures>
    <str:Codelists>
      <str:Codelist version="2017" isExternalReference="none" isFinal="none" agencyID="ICONICS" id="SSP" urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Codelist=ICONICS:SSP(2017)">
        <com:Name xml:lang="en">Shared Socioeconomic Pathways (2017 edition)</com:Name>
        <com:Description xml:lang="en">This code list is *not* officially published by ICONICS; rather, it is a rendering into SDMX of structural information that is provided by ICONICS participants. It may change or be superseded at any time.  Each code has a single digit ID like "1"; the "original-id" annotation (and the start of the name) give a string like "SSP1". These original IDs are *only* unique if using data enumerated by solely by one code list or the other; if mixing the two, then they will be ambiguous. The URNs of the codes or parts thereof (for instance, "ICONICS:SSP(2017).1") are, by construction, unique.

This is the original set of SSPs as described in https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2016.05.009.</com:Description>
        <str:Code id="1" urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=ICONICS:SSP(2017).1">
          <com:Annotations>
            <com:Annotation id="original-id">
              <com:AnnotationText xml:lang="en">SSP1</com:AnnotationText>
            </com:Annotation>
          </com:Annotations>
          <com:Name xml:lang="en">SSP1: Sustainability</com:Name>
          <com:Description xml:lang="en">SSP1: Sustainability &#8211; Taking the Green Road

Low challenges to mitigation and adaptation.

The world shifts gradually, but pervasively, toward a more sustainable path, emphasizing
more inclusive development that respects perceived environmental boundaries. Management
of the global commons slowly improves, educational and health investments accelerate the
demographic transition, and the emphasis on economic growth shifts toward a broader
emphasis on human well-being. Driven by an increasing commitment to achieving
development goals, inequality is reduced both across and within countries. Consumption
is oriented toward low material growth and lower resource and energy intensity.</com:Description>
        </str:Code>
        <str:Code id="2" urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=ICONICS:SSP(2017).2">
          <com:Annotations>
            <com:Annotation id="original-id">
              <com:AnnotationText xml:lang="en">SSP2</com:AnnotationText>
            </com:Annotation>
          </com:Annotations>
          <com:Name xml:lang="en">SSP2: Middle of the Road</com:Name>
          <com:Description xml:lang="en">SSP2: Middle of the Road

Medium challenges to mitigation and adaptation.

The world follows a path in which social, economic, and technological trends do not
shift markedly from historical patterns. Development and income growth proceeds
unevenly, with some countries making relatively good progress while others fall short of
expectations. Global and national institutions work toward but make slow progress in
achieving sustainable development goals. Environmental systems experience degradation,
although there are some improvements and overall the intensity of resource and energy
use declines. Global population growth is moderate and levels off in the second half of
the century. Income inequality persists or improves only slowly and challenges to
reducing vulnerability to societal and environmental changes remain.</com:Description>
        </str:Code>
        <str:Code id="3" urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=ICONICS:SSP(2017).3">
          <com:Annotations>
            <com:Annotation id="original-id">
              <com:AnnotationText xml:lang="en">SSP3</com:AnnotationText>
            </com:Annotation>
          </com:Annotations>
          <com:Name xml:lang="en">SSP3: Regional Rivalry</com:Name>
          <com:Description xml:lang="en">SSP3: Regional Rivalry &#8211; A Rocky Road

High challenges to mitigation and adaptation.

A resurgent nationalism, concerns about competitiveness and security, and regional
conflicts push countries to increasingly focus on domestic or, at most, regional issues.
Policies shift over time to become increasingly oriented toward national and regional
security issues. Countries focus on achieving energy and food security goals within
their own regions at the expense of broader-based development. Investments in education
and technological development decline. Economic development is slow, consumption is
material-intensive, and inequalities persist or worsen over time. Population growth is
low in industrialized and high in developing countries. A low international priority for
addressing environmental concerns leads to strong environmental degradation in some
regions.</com:Description>
        </str:Code>
        <str:Code id="4" urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=ICONICS:SSP(2017).4">
          <com:Annotations>
            <com:Annotation id="original-id">
              <com:AnnotationText xml:lang="en">SSP4</com:AnnotationText>
            </com:Annotation>
          </com:Annotations>
          <com:Name xml:lang="en">SSP4: Inequality</com:Name>
          <com:Description xml:lang="en">SSP4: Inequality &#8211; A Road Divided

Low challenges to mitigation, high challenges to adaptation.

Highly unequal investments in human capital, combined with increasing disparities in
economic opportunity and political power, lead to increasing inequalities and
stratification both across and within countries. Over time, a gap widens between an
internationally-connected society that contributes to knowledge- and capital-intensive
sectors of the global economy, and a fragmented collection of lower-income, poorly
educated societies that work in a labor intensive, low-tech economy. Social cohesion
degrades and conflict and unrest become increasingly common. Technology development is
high in the high-tech economy and sectors. The globally connected energy sector
diversifies, with investments in both carbon-intensive fuels like coal and
unconventional oil, but also low-carbon energy sources. Environmental policies focus on
local issues around middle and high income areas.</com:Description>
        </str:Code>
        <str:Code id="5" urn="urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.codelist.Code=ICONICS:SSP(2017).5">
          <com:Annotations>
            <com:Annotation id="original-id">
              <com:AnnotationText xml:lang="en">SSP5</com:AnnotationText>
            </com:Annotation>
          </com:Annotations>
          <com:Name xml:lang="en">SSP5: Fossil-fueled Development</com:Name>
          <com:Description xml:lang="en">SSP5: Fossil-fueled Development &#8211; Taking the Highway

High challenges to mitigation, low challenges to adaptation.

This world places increasing faith in competitive markets, innovation and participatory
societies to produce rapid technological progress and development of human capital as
the path to sustainable development. Global markets are increasingly integrated. There
are also strong investments in health, education, and institutions to enhance human and
social capital. At the same time, the push for economic and social development is
coupled with the exploitation of abundant fossil fuel resources and the adoption of
resource and energy intensive lifestyles around the world. All these factors lead to
rapid growth of the global economy, while global population peaks and declines in the
21st century. Local environmental problems like air pollution are successfully managed.
There is faith in the ability to effectively manage social and ecological systems,
including by geo-engineering if necessary.</com:Description>
        </str:Code>
      </str:Codelist>
    </str:Codelists>
  </mes:Structures>
</mes:Structure>
